Guide to the American Public Health Association Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- SECTION ON MEDICAL CARE, SUBCOMMITTEE ON MEDICAL CARE, 1948-1972; Series II; 3 linear feet (6 boxes)
  - General Papers
    - Handbook for section council and committee chairmen, 1968 October (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence and memoranda re: C.A.F.O.R., 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Agenda and reports of Governing Council meeting, 1969 November 9, 12 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence of section council meeting, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Minutes and related material of Technical Development Board, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Section newsletters, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence re: awards, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence and memoranda re: awards, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence re: section council nominations, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Section newsletters, 1970 January-October (Box 8, Folder 25-26)
    - Agenda and reports of Governing Council meeting, 1970 October 25, 28 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Minutes, memoranda and correspondence of section council meeting, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Annual reports, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Abstracts of papers and correspondence for annual meeting, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Fact sheets of Student American Medical Association, 1971 January-March (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence and notes for annual meeting, 1971 January-September (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, memoranda and notes for annual meeting, 1971 April-November (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Memoranda, correspondence and program for annual meeting, 1971 October-November (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Memoranda, agenda and correspondence of section council meeting, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence re: The Nation's Health, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Minutes, correspondence and memoranda for annual meeting, 1972 January-November (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Proposed outline and preface for Guide to Medical Care Administration, vol. II: "Guidelines for Action", undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Committee and Council Files
    - Committee on Eligibility: correspondence, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Committee on Equal Health Rights
      - Correspondence and resolutions, 1968-1969 June (Box 10, Folder 43)
      - Correspondence, resolutions and lists, 1969 July-December (Box 10, Folder 44)
      - Correspondence, minutes and lists, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Committee on Health Services Research: correspondence and lists, 1968-1972, undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Committee on International Medical Care
      - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 47)
      - Correspondence, minutes and list, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 48)
      - Correspondence, report and lists, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 49)
      - Correspondence and lists, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Committee on Long-Range Planning: correspondence, reports and lists, 1968-1971 (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Committee on Membership and Regional Involvement
      - Correspondence and lists, 1968-1969 June (Box 10, Folder 52)
      - Correspondence, 1969 July-December (Box 10, Folder 53)
      - Correspondence and report, 1970 January-June (Box 10, Folder 54)
      - Correspondence and list, 1970 July-December (Box 10, Folder 55)
      - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 56)
      - Correspondence, drafts and miscellaneous material, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Committee of nominations
      - Correspondence, lists and related material, 1968-1969 May-December (Box 10, Folder 58-59)
      - Correspondence and related material, 1970 January-April (Box 11, Folder 60)
      - Correspondence, 1970 May-July (Box 11, Folder 61)
      - Correspondence, lists and related material, 1970 August - 1971 (Box 11, Folder 62)
      - Correspondence and related material, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Committee on Program
      - Correspondence and related material, 1967-1970 January-Oct, 1971 February - 1972, undated (Box 11, Folder 64-69)
    - Committee on Publications: correspondence, lists and miscellaneous material, 1968-1969, undated (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - Committee on Social Policy and Resolutions
      - Correspondence and resolutions, 1959, 1968-1970 January-August (Box 12, Folder 71-74)
      - Correspondence, resolutions and list, 1970 October-December (Box 12, Folder 75)
      - Correspondence, resolutions and list, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 76)
      - Correspondence and resolutions, 1972, undated (Box 12, Folder 77)
    - Council on Personal Health Services: correspondence and related material, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 78)
    - Joint Committee on Medical Care Education: correspondence, minutes and lists, 1968-1970 (Box 12, Folder 79)
    - Medical Care Editorial Board: correspondence and reports, 1965-1969 (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - Medical Care Editorial Board: correspondence and reports, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - National New Professional Health Workers: correspondence and related material, 1970-1971, undated (Box 12, Folder 82)
- BACKGROUND AND RESEARCH MATERIAL, 1938-1972; Series III; 1.5 linear feet (3 boxes)
  Series III is organized in four sections: Subcommittee on Medical Care, A.P.H.A. General, Other Papers, and Notes and Drafts. Each section is arranged chronologically.
  - Subcommittee on Medical Care
    - Subcommittee on the Organized Care of the Sick, C.A.P., 1939-1945, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Joseph Mountin Mss. [with related material], 1940-1946 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Subcommittee on Medical Care, 1943-1946 (Box 13, Folder 3-5)
    - Medical care minutes, 1946-1950, 1952, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Subcommittee on Medical Care, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Maryland Medical Care Program, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Regionalization in New England, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - "Quality of Medical Care in a National Health Program,", 1949 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Subcommittee on Medical Care, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Health Insurance - medical care programs, Falk reprint, British Columbia, 1950 February (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Medical care (miscellaneous), 1957, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - A.P.H.A. General
    - A.P.H.A. Executive Board, 1948-1950 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - C.A.P. reports to Governing Council, 1948-1952 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - A.P.H.A. Executive Board, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Other Papers
    - American Public Welfare Association, 1938-1939 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Committee on the Hygiene of Housing (R. F. Voell), 1938-1941 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - "Medical Care for Recipients of Public Assistance in Westchester County, New York" (L. S. Reed, D. A. Clark), 1940 September (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - American Public Welfare Association, 1940-1959 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Committee of Physicians, 1946-1949, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - President's Committee on National Employment of the Physically Handicapped Week, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Joint Committee on the Coordination of Hospitals and Health Departments, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - The Physicians Forum, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Subcommittee on Federal-State-Local Relationships -- also Expansion of the Evaluation Schedule, 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Conference on Medical Care, Teaching, 1950-1955 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Chronic disease, 1950-1957 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Goldmann letter, 1954 September 2 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Conference on Medical Care Teaching, 1956-1958 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Notes and Drafts
    - Medical Care Section paper: topical outline, A.P.H.A. presentation, Circa 1971 June (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Interviews, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous notes and background material, Circa 1935-1970 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Reprint: Arthur J. Viseltear, "Emergence of the Medical Care Section of the American Public Health Association,", 1972 (Box 15, Folder 33)